Guide to the Cornell Concert Commission records 1971-2017.
Cornell Concert Commission records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Concert Commission records 1971-2017.
37-7-3832
Cornell Concert Commission
3 cubic feet
7 items
Newspapers, photocopies, photographs, scrapbooks.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Material documenting the shows and operations of the Cornell Concert Commission mostly from 1971-1992, includes tour riders, posters, advertising material, and scrapbooks.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Material documenting the shows and operations of the Cornell Concert Commission mostly from 1971-1992, includes tour riders, posters, advertising material, and scrapbooks.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Concert Commission; Cornell University -- Students.; Grateful Dead (Musical group); Cornell University; Chodock, Robert,; Kibrick, Howard
Subjects:
Concerts.; Rock concerts.; Rock music.; Students
Form and Genre Terms:
Posters.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Concert Files
Series II. Scrapbooks
Series III. Posters
Series IV. Assorted Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Concert Files
  Includes tour riders, publicity material, correspondence, financial records, crew lists, newspaper clippings, and show advertisments
  - Aretha Franklin, 1971-09-17 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Tour rider includes clause emphasizing no all white audiences
  - Sha Na Na; Jim Spherris, 1972-02-26 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jethro Tull; Wild Turkey, 1972-04-15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Elton John, 1972-09-26 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Includes notes on incidents during show
  - Blood, Sweat & Tears; Charlie Starr, 1972-10-20 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Beach Boys, 1972-11-17 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Byrds, 1973-02-10 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - John McLaughlin, 1973-02-23 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Loggins & Messina, 1973-03-11 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stevie Wonder, 1973-03-30 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Arlo Gutherie, 1973-04-14 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Seatrain, 1973-05-07 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Deep Purple, 1973-06-12 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Emerson, Lake and Palmer, 1973-07-13 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fall '73 Concerts, 1973-09-1973-12 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Paul Simon; Urubama; Jesse Dixon Singers, 1973-10-19 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Sly & the Family Stone; the Wailers, 1973-11-03 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Judy Collins, 1973-11-17 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Emerson, Lake and Palmer, 1973-12-08 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Press release regarding show cancellation, mentions financial settlement discussions from Deep Purple show
  - Joni Mitchell, 1974-02-03 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Yes; John Martyn, 1974-02-24 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - The Four Tops, 1974-03-02 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Cancelled
  - Temptations, 1974-03-02 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Jefferson Starship, 1974-03-31 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gregg Allman; Cowboy; Boyer & Tarlton, 1974-04-16 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cornell Folk Festival, 1974-04-19-1974-04-20 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Creative Source; Voices of East Harlem; New Birth, 1974-05-10 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Leon Russell, 1974-05-11 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Martin Mull, 1974-05-13 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - The Band, 1974-09-04 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Santana, 1974-10-14 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Taj Mahal with Minnie Ripperton, 1974-10-26 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Taj Mahal with Minnie Ripperton, 1974-10-26 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Cornell Jazz Festival, 1974-11-16 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Billy Joel and Wendy Waldman, 1974-12-07 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Jackson Browne and Phoebe Snow, 1975-03-15 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Jackson Browne and Phoebe Snow, 1975-03-15 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Herbie Hancock, 1975-04-05 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Miles Davis cancelled
  - Cornell Folk Festival, 1975-04-18-1975-04-19 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Donald Byrd and the Blackbyrds, 1975-05-10 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - National Lampoon Show, 1975-09-26 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest, 1975-10-24 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Jerry Garcia Band, 1975-10-27 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Beach Boys, 1975-11-17 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Royal Shakespeare Company, 1975-11-18 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Beach Boys, 1975-11-27 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Melissa Manchester with Eric Andersen, 1976-04-11 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Renaissance, 1976-04-24 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Loggins & Messina, 1976-05-08 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - New Riders of the Purple Sage, 1976-10-31 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Tour rider includes suggestion to hire "two ladies" to serve as hostesses
  - Seals & Crofts, 1976-11-12 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - David Bromberg Band; Kenny Rankin, 1977-03-12 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - The New Commander Cody Band, 1977-05-06 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Grateful Dead, 1977-05-08 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Linda Ronstadt, 1977-10-27 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Includes note about "the ridiculous audience control pattern"
  - Renaissance, 1977-11-01 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Marshall Tucker Band, 1977-12-11 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Emerson, Lake & Palmer, 1978-01-30 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Tour rider includes detailed food requests
  - Pete Seeger, 1978-04-15 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Marshall Tucker Band, 1978-04-23 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Springfest schedule, 1978-05-04-1978-05-08 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Sea Level; Horslips, 1978-05-05 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Meat Loaf, 1978-05-08 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Robert Palmer; Robert Hunter, 1978-05-08 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Doobie Brothers, 1978-09-29 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Tour rider includes request for 500 lbs. of dry ice
  - Robert Klein; Stanky Brown Group, 1978-10-05 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Patti Smith Group, 1978-10-14 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Bruce Springsteen, 1978-11-07 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Boston; Sammy Hagar, 1978-11-17 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Heart, 1979-01-28 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Tour rider includes request for 350 lbs. of dry ice; emphasis placed on organic foods
  - The Kinks, 1979-02-23 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Includes concert t-shirt sketches
  - Southside Johnny and the Asbury Jukes, 1979-03-09 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Renaissance, 1979-04-27 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Springfest, 1979-05-04 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    Wet Willie; Stanky Brown
  - Joe Jackson; the Records, 1979-09-14 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Cars, 1979-10-07 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Chick Corea and Gary Burton, 1979-10-19 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Laughing Dogs; the Sinceros, 1979-10-25 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Stanley Clarke with friends, 1979-11-10 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - The Police; Steel Pulse, 1979-11-30 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Cindy Bullens, 1979-12-07 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Steve Forbert, 1980-02-09 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Dave Mason; Hans Olson, 1980-02-15 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - The Kinks; Steve Forbert, 1980-03-02 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    Includes flyers advertising WVBR's Romeo and Juliet contest to pair up strangers for dinner and the concert
  - Warren Zevon, 1980-04-11 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - The Pretenders, 1980-05-02 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - The Grateful Dead, 1980-05-07 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    Tour rider includes clause refusing to perform before audiences segregated on the basis of race, color, creed or sex
  - B. Willie Smith, 1980-05-15 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Steve Forbert, 1980-10-02 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Al Jarreau, 1980-10-18 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Utopia, 1980-11-06 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - George Thorogood; the Destroyers, 1980-11-08 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - The Ramones, 1981-02-28 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Pat Metheny, 1981-03-16 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - The Grateful Dead, 1981-05-16 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    Includes memo detailing injuries from this concert and Kinks show
  - Utopia, 1981-11-06 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Utopia, 1981-11-06 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Allman Brothers, 1981-12-06 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - George Thorogood; the Delaware Destroyers, 1984-12-08 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Echo & the Bunnymen; the Leather Nun, 1988-02-07 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Megadeth; Warlock; Sanctuary, 1988-04-17 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Tour rider prohibits "Slam Dancing and Stage Diving".
  - UB40; Untouchables, 1988-10-18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Student Assembly commends Cornell Concert Commission, claiming "the group stirred up more excitement on campus than any group has in years… you have quieted, for a time, the many students who clamor for big-name bands to come on campus". Enclosed is a form detailing a poster violation filed by the Robert Purcell Union (along with copy of offending poster).
  - Tracy Chapman; John Hammond, 1988-11-22 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Tracy Chapman had "just concluded performing with the Amnesty International Tour all over the world, and [had] scheduled only five shoes in the Western Hemisphere, one of which is at Cornell".
  - Wynton Marsalis, 1988-12-03 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Contract prohibits the presence of a piano "in the artist's suite".
  - Stanley Jordan, 1989-02-18 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Includes ballot for election of Cornell Concert Commission Executive Board.
  - Ladysmith Black Mambazo; Samite, 1989-03-06 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Edie Bricknell & New Bohemians; Steve Forbert, 1989-04-09 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Tito Puente; De La Soul, 1989-04-16 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Concert was co-presented by the Third World Student Programming Board.
  - Springfest, 1989-05-05; SR-6349, SR-20742 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Performers: the Toasters; the Feelies; Includes two 7" vinyl records featuring The Toaster's "Talk Is Cheap", and a letter discussing the possibility of hosting a summer venue at Schoelkopf Field.
  - Joe Jackson, 1989-09-27 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Artist specifically agreed to perform, "An Evening With" (see additional provisions in contract).
  - Reggaefest, 1989-11-10 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Performers: Third World; Soul Jahs; bop (harvey)
  - The Alarm; The Kevin McDermott Orchestra, 1989-12-07 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Erasure, 1990-02-22 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes letter detailing a theft that took place after the concert, and very detailed advertising routes for Cornell Concert Commission members.
  - Robert Fripp & The League of Crafty Guitarists, 1990-04-01 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Includes letter describing artist's appreciation for Cornell University's excellent hospitality and cetering services, and index cards with reviews of the concert
  - MTV's Save the Earth Campaign, 1990-04-02-1990-04-06 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes information regarding the MTV Save the Earth Campaign; stickers from the event, a copy of the April edition of MTV To Go, along with an essay of sorts titled "CIJ on being a woman in the music industry".
  - Hugh Masekela, 1990-04-29 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Springfest, 1990-05-04 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Performer: NBRQ, Cancelled
  - Saturn V Laser Light Concert, 1990-08-24 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Midnight Oil; The Origin, 1990-09-30 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Little Feat; Joe Ely, 1990-10-14 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    The Joe Ely tour rider explicitly demands "no insects or animal organs - please!"
  - Yo! MTV Raps, 1990-10-26 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Branford Marsalis, 1990-11-11 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Indigo Girls, 1990-12-06 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Indigo Girls, 1990-12-07 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Timothy Wright (and the Concert Choir); The Wade Sisters, Lorraine Stancil, 1991-02-08 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Living Colour; Urban Dance Squad, 1991-02-17 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Spyro Gyra; Jay Beckenstein, 1991-04-14 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Boogie Down Productions; Ed O.G.; Da Bulldogs, 1991-04-19 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Commercial thirty seconds in length was broadcasted on MTV and ESPN sometime between 6 AM and midnight
  - Group Effort, 1991-04-23 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Original date of concert April 23, 1991 was cancelled, reschedule form does not indicate new date
  - Bernie Milton and the Soul Patrol, 1991-08-23 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Jesus Jones; Ned's Atomic Dustbin, 1991-10-06 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Squeeze; Katydids, 1991-10-27 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Crosby & Nash, 1991-11-17 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Vanessa Bell Armstrong; Last Appeal (Cancelled), 1992-02-07 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Involved collaboration between Cornell Concert Commission and the Festival of Black Gospel Committee; cancelled because record label did not respond in time. Includes resume of William David Stewart, a gospel singer. Enclosed is a letter from the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority requesting funds to host "The Boy's Choir of Harlem".
  - Naughty by Nature, Queen Latifah, and Blacksheep, 1992-03-29 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    The Flavor Unit Tour
  - 10,000 Maniacs; The Heartbeats, 1992-04-10 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - The Show From Hell (Brash '92), 1992-05-03 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Performers: Violent Femmes, Fishbone, Blue yster Cult, and Tribe. Transcripts of WJPZ Syracuse radio broadcasts of this event are included.
  - The Show From Hell (Brash '92), 1992-05-03 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - The Show From Hell (Brash '92), 1992-05-03 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    Includes an investigation report detailing two incidents involving minors; "the seventeen year old has a possible broken ankle… [and] the sixteen year old was kicked in the head…"
  - Chick Corea Akoustic Band + One, 1992-09-25 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Scrapbooks, 1972-1989
  - Scrapbook, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    Includes Elton John. Jason, Blood Sweat and Tears, Beach Boys, The Byrds, Herbie Hancock, Miles Davis, Bobby Byrd and the JB's, Mahavishnu Orchestra, Loggins and Messina, Deep Purple has information about the riot during the show.
  - Scrapbook, 1973 (Box 1)
    Includes various acts, some clippings for concerts from performers who came to Cornell, but not necessarily for their Cornell performance.
  - Scrapbook, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    Includes Joni Mitchell, Yes, Four Tops, Jefferson Starship, The Mahavishnu Orchestra and Weather Report, Judy Collins, Paul Simon, Sly and the Family Stone, David Crosby and Graham Nash, The Band with Aztec Two-Step, Santana, Taj Mahal with Minnie Ripperton, Return to Forever with Chick Corea, The Eleventh House with Larry Coryell, Billy Joel.
  - Scrapbook, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    Includes Linda Ronstadt, Renaissance, New Riders of the Purple Sage, Grateful Dead.
  - Scrapbook, 1989 (Box 1)
    Includes Stanley Jordan, Lady Smith Black Mambazo with Samite, Edie Brickell and New Bohemians, Tito Puente and De La Soul.
- Posters, 1972-1979, 1985-1989
  - Pamela Polland, Date Unknown (Folder 2)
  - Miles Davis, Herbie Hancock, Date Unknown (Folder 2)
    Count: 3
  - Mahavishnu Orchestra, Weather Report (Folder 2)
  - Elton John, David Johnstone, Dee Murray, Nigel Olsson and Family, 1972-09-26 (Folder 2)
  - The Mahavishnu Orchestra with John McLaughlin, 1973-02-23 (Folder 2)
    Count: 2
  - Loggins and Messina, 1973-03-11 (Folder 2)
  - Stevie Wonder, the Persuasions, 1973-03-30 (Folder 2)
  - Deep Purple, Billy Preston and Family, 1973-06-02 (Folder 2)
  - Crosby & Nash, 1973-09-05 (Folder 2)
    Freshman Week Concert
  - Paul Simon, Urubamba, Jesse Dixson Singers, 1973-10-19 (Folder 2)
  - Sly & the Family Stone, 1973-11-03 (Folder 2)
  - Judy Collins, 1973-11-17 (Folder 2)
  - Emerson, Lake, & Palmer, 1973-12-08 (Folder 2)
    Count: 4
  - Joni Mitchell, Tom Scott, L.A. Express, 1974-02-03 (Folder 3)
  - Yes, 1974-02-24 (Folder 3)
    Count: 12
  - Four Tops, the Voices of East Harlem, 1974-03-02 (Folder 3)
    Count: 6
  - Jefferson Starship, John Barbata, Papa John Creach, Peter Kangaroo, David Freiberg, Craig Chaquiso, Grace Slick, Paul Kantner, 1974-03-31 (Folder 3)
    Count: 8
  - Gregg Allman, Cowboy, Boyer & Talton, 1974-04-16 (Folder 3)
    Count: 5
  - Spring Weekend '74, 1974-05-10-1974-05-13 (Folder 4)
    The New Birth, Creative Source, The Voices of East Harlem, Leon Russell, The Fab Furniture of Martin Mull; Count: 4
  - Leon Russell, 1974-05-11 (Folder 4)
  - The Band, Renaissance, 1974-09-04 (Folder 4)
  - Santana, 1974-10-14 (Folder 4)
  - Cornell Jazz Festival '74, 1974-11-16 (Folder 4)
    Return to Forever featuring Chick Corea, the Eleventh House featuring Larry Coryell, Michael Urbaniak and Fusion; Count: 3
  - Billy Joel, 1974-12-07 (Folder 4)
  - Jackson Browne, Phoebe Snow, 1975-03-15 (Folder 4)
  - Jackson Browne, Phoebe Snow, 1975-03-15 (Folder 4)
  - Folk Festival '75, 1975-04-18-1975-04-19 (Folder 4)
    Jim Rooney and Partners in Crime, Johnny Shines, Tracy Nelson and Mother Earth, Bryan Bowers, Arlo Guthrie, David Amram, Jay and Lyn Ungar, Furry Lewis, Tom Paxton, Vassar Clements, Loudon Wainwright III; Count: 2
  - Grateful Dead, 1978-09-04 (Folder 4)
  - Marshall Tucker Band, 1978-12-11 (Folder 4)
  - Renaissance, 1979-04-24 (Folder 4)
  - The Wynton Marsalis Quintet, 1985-02-06 (Folder 1)
  - Jean-Luc Ponty, 1985-03-08 (Folder 1)
  - Joan Armatrading, 1985-04-28 (Folder 1)
  - Spring Fest '85, 1985-05-10 (Folder 1)
    Southside Johnny & the Asbury Jukes; Count: 2
  - Patrick Moraz, Bill Bruford, 1985-09-19 (Folder 1)
  - B.B. King, 1985-09-29 (Folder 1)
  - Suzanne Vega, Mercy Seat, 1986-10-25 (Folder 1)
  - Lisa Lisa & Cult Jam, 1987-04-12 (Folder 1)
  - Tracy Chapman, John Hammond, 1988-11-22 (Folder 1)
  - Ladysmith Black Mambazo, Samite, 1989-03-06 (Folder 1)
  - Edie Brickell & New Bohemians, Steve Forbert, 1989-04-09 (Folder 1)
- Assorted Files
  - Assorted photos and clippings (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Band Receipts, 1992-03-12-1992-11-23 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Grateful Dead Barton Hall accounts, 2016-03-01-2016-08-11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Accounts written in 2016 describe May 8, 1977 concert
  - Grateful Dead photos, 2017-05; Jon Reis (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Reprint photos of May 8, 1977 concert at Barton Hall